Are you planning to buy ICICI Prudential
iProtect Smart Term Plan, then
before that, definitely watch this video.
In this video, we will discuss all the features and benefits of this plan
and will also see whether we should buy this plan or
not. ICICI
Prudential is the third largest
insurance company in India by volume and its
claim settlement ratio is more than 97%. There
is no limit on the minimum term of 50 years and the maximum term in this plan. It
depends on your annual income, which can be
10 to 25 times of your annual income.
In this policy, you get a minimum term of 5
years and a maximum term of 40 years. Along with this,
you also get a full life cover
which covers you till 99 years.
To pay the premium, monthly, half yearly and
annual end options are available to you.
To pay the policy, you have the
options of regular pay, single pay and limited pay.  This
means that you are paying the premium for the number of
years for which you have taken the policy.
Limited pay means that your
cover continues for the number of years for which you have taken the policy,
but
you pay its premium for some limited number of years. For
limited pay, you have the
options of five pay, seven pay, 10 pay.
Along with this, you also have the option of one point 60, in
which you
pay the premium till your retirement and
your cover continues for whatever number of years you have taken, i.e.,
₹65. Along with this, there is
another option of
single pay, in which you pay the premium for the inter-policy term
in a single premium.
If the premium features are inbuilt,
when the doctor declares that the
patient is bound to die within 6-8 months or in a few months,
in case of terminal illness, you get the
payout of your premium even before your death. The
second benefit is
permanent disability, if any permanent disability occurs due to an accident.  If
disability occurs,
all your future premiums are waived.
You do not have to pay any premium
further and your policy cover continues
till the end term. Next
is the option
which can be up to twice your basic sum.
Due to being built-in, the premium of the Live Plus option is
slightly lower than the premium of the Life option. Life and Health option:
In this variant, along with the life option,
critical illness benefits will also be available.
This plan covers 34 critical illnesses, in
which if
any one of these 30 listed diseases is detected,
your critical illness is
paid out to you in lumpsum.
In this variant, a critical illness is an accelerated
benefit and not an additional benefit. This
means that whatever critical illness is paid out is
from your term insurance coverage. For example, suppose
you have a policy of Rs 1 crore and there is an
accelerated benefit related to critical allergies of Rs 10 lakh.
So, if any  If
you are diagnosed with a critical illness, the
payout of just Rs 10 lakh will be from your term
insurance, and your death
benefit will remain at Rs 90 lakh. This is the only
feature of this plan that I don't like because
its critical benefits
should be separate, additional,
not accelerated. If you are taking this term plan,
you
can take a critical policy separately along with your health insurance,
which also provides you with more comprehensive
benefits. The next
variant is the all-in-one option, in which
all the features of all three variants will be available,
such as payout on terminal illness, fee
of premium, accidental death benefit,
and accelerated critical illness benefit. The
more features a plan has, the
higher its premium. You
can select your term plan according to your needs and budget. You
also get the option of increasing income. The
loss option is
lump sum. You can take the income option in one go
and the remaining benefit for 9 years.  You will have to
take monthly installments. Another option is
Increasing Income, in which we get
monthly installments for 10 years
and it increases by 10% every year. If
your family is not financially aware or
cannot handle such a large amount,
then you should select the Income or
Increasing Income option.
If your family or your
nominee can handle such a large amount
or you have taken a big loan, then
in such a case you should select the Lumpsum option.
In this plan, we
get the option of Life Term Protection, in
which we can increase our responsibilities as well as
our time savings.
In case of marriage, we can increase our sum assured by up to 50%,
in case of first child, by 25% maximum up to Rs. 25
lakh and in case of second child also, by 25% maximum up
to Rs. 25 lakh.
This term
is also in our list of top five term plans. If
you want, definitely consider this plan.
If you have any doubt related to term insurance, health
insurance or investment, then
you
can ask by commenting below or you can
also ask by messaging on our WhatsApp number. If
you liked the video, then definitely like it and
subscribe to the channel. See you
in the next video. Thank you.